嗯 薄饼闻起来不错哟
Those pancakes smell great.
你穿那些是要上哪儿啊
What are you doing with those?
卢克和我准备开车去收旧东西
Luke and I are doing a recycling drive.
如果能收到够多的瓶子
If we collect enough bottles
就可以在非洲建一所学校了
they build a school in Africa.
要是能读一所
Wouldn't that be so cool
用瓶子堆起来的学校就太给力了
to go to a school made out of bottles?
那铁定是所特殊学校
That would certainly be a special school.
你们有听到我说什么没 爹妈
Did you hear what I said, parents?
"特殊学校"
"Special school"?
好吧 大家先别太大反应
Okay, nobody make a big deal about it,
我和迪兰分了
but I just broke up with Dylan.
-别啊 -老天 你没事吧 宝贝
- No - Oh, my gosh. Are you okay, honey?
嗯 没事 我只是
Yeah, I'm fine. I just
我得找个聪明灵活点的男朋友
I need to date someone who has a clue,
而迪兰就是个傻瓜
instead of an idiot
每次把车骑出车库时都要撞到头
who bangs his head every time he rides his bike out of his garage
每次都是
Every time!
真为你难过 宝贝
I'm sorry, honey.
我为你俩感到难过
I'm sorry for both of you.
我一会儿发短信安慰一下他
I'll have to text him later.
嗯 我得去洗澡了 要迟了
Mmm. I gotta jump in the shower. I'm gonna be late.
要去哪儿啊
Where are you going?
去见我的好朋友 瓦莱丽
I'm going to meet my friend Valerie.
我们15年没见了
I haven't seen her in 15 years.
我们之前是同事来着
We used to work together.
-你上过班? -嗯哼
-You worked? -Mm-hmm.
想不出来你上班是什么样子
Can't imagine you working.
卢克 我跟你说
Luke, let me tell you something.
这样对女性说话很不礼貌
That is very offensive to women.
你老妈工作时很卖力
Your mom works very hard.
只是她现在选择照顾我们
It's just now she works for us.
跟你们说 当年我可是前途大好
I will have you know that I had quite the little career going.
我那时可是星冠酒店的客户经理
I was an account manager at Starcrest Hotels.
我有自己的小单间
I had a little cubicle,
我先穿运动鞋去上班
and-and I wore my tennis shoes to work...
然后换成工作装
and changed into my work pumps.
跟电影《上班女郎》一样
It was very Working Girl.
-那部电影真赞 -嗯哼
- That movie's so clutch - Mm-hmm.
可以说 我当年那叫一个宏图大展啊
I don't mind saying I was making quite a splash.
那你为什么不干了呢
Well, then, why'd you quit?
海莉 你可以说我守旧
Well, Haley, call me old-fashioned,
但我想全心顾家
but I wanted to focus on raising a family.
所以我嫁给了你老爸
So I married your dad.
过了五个月以后 我们就 就
Five months later, we... were...
又过了四个月 有了这个小美人
four months away from having this little bundle of joy.
嗯嗯
Mm-hmm.
我家大律师驾到
There's my lawyer.
歌洛莉亚出了场小车祸
Gloria got into a little car accident,
我爸让我帮她处理下
so my dad asked me to help her out.
这是第一次
And, uh, this is the first
我爸向我请求法律援助
time that my dad's asked me for legal advice,
感觉很不错
and it's-it's nice.
那让我觉得他还是很尊重我的工作的
It's nice to know that he respects me in that way.
米奇尔是个超棒的律师
Well, Mitchell is an amazing lawyer.
我梦想他能进最高法院
My dream for him is that one day he'll be on the Supreme Court.
为啥 小卡
Why, Cam?
那样参加派对时
So at parties
我就可以向大家卖弄我男友"法力高强"
I can tell everyone my partner is one of the Supremes.
瞧瞧 精壮如钢铁的灰发老朽
There he is-the steely, grizzled veteran...
要和勇猛小胖星大干一场
ready to do battle with the plucky upstart.
速度对战优雅
Speed versus grace.
-野性战... -直接办正事儿吧
-Brute force versus -Let's just do this.
杰和我都喜欢健身
Jay and I are both gym rats.
我爱桑拿那种干热的感觉
I love the sauna. That's the dry heat.
还有湿热的蒸汽
And the steam, wet.
我也超迷手球式墙球的
And, of course, I am just a kook for racquetball.
连续两年拿俱乐部冠军
Club champ two years in a row,
在密苏里州通加诺克西的健康中心
Tonganoxie, Missouri Rec Center.
所以杰和我这几个月都在计划
So, naturally, Jay and I have been trying for months...
一起去打一场球赛
to get together to bang the old hollow rubber ball around.
我真是竭尽全力在躲那场比赛
I have been avoiding this day like the plague.
去健身 一方面是冲着那种气氛
I mean, part of going to the gym is the lockerroom atmosphere.
但如果身边有一个基佬
And if I'm there with a gay guy,
气氛就完全毁了
it's-it's just not gonna be the same.
对我来说 更衣室就是更衣室
I mean, for me, it's a locker room.
但对他 就是脱衣舞厅
For him, it's a showroom.
她不懂的
She doesn't get it.
*开着我的小车呀*
*Driving in my car*
*给你看我的伤疤*
*I'll let you see my scar*
搞毛啊
What the hell?
有人说我是销售员
Some people call me a salesman.
我觉得自己是"销售之友"
I call myself a sales friend.
显然 我需要陌生人能够信任我
So obviously, I need strangers to trust me.
因此我觉得很不爽
I don't take kindly to it
因为有人给我画上汤姆·希莱克斯那样的胡子
when someone Tom Sellecks my bus bench.
我是菲尔·邓菲
Phil Dunphy.
菲尔 我是芭芭拉
Phil, it's Barbara.
帕特森一家不想买了
The Pattersons wanna back out of the deal.
为什么 出什么事了
Why? What happened?
他家老婆犹豫了
The wife's getting cold feet.
-我让她打给你了 -好吧
-I told her to call you. -Okay, fine.
我来处理吧 我绝不能丢掉这一单
I'll handle it. I'm not losing this sale.
-另外 -我可是花了大量心血啊
-By the way -I've spent way too much time on it.
菲尔 你上班经过榆树街吗
Phil, do you take Elm when you come to work?
我看见了 芭芭拉
I saw it, Barbara.
健身房不错嘛 杰
It's a terrific gym, Jay.
毛巾随便用 我喜欢
Very liberal with the towels. I love that.
淋浴室单间的 先告诉你一声
Showers are private, in case you wondered.
我没想那个 不过谢谢你的提醒
I wasn't, but thanks for the heads-up.
真是惊奇呀 宽松平角裤
Now, that's a surprise. Boxers.
你有必要吗
Is that necessary?
我只是一直想象 你应该是穿紧身白色内裤的
Well, I just always pictured you as a tighty-whitey guy.
求求你了 下次你想象时
Well, do me a favor. The next time you picture me,
别想我的内裤
leave the underwear out of it.
别担心 我想象也只是会想
Well, don't you worry. The only thing I'm picturing...
我要是拿你拖地 那会拖得多干净
is how clean the floor's gonna be when I'm done mopping it with you.
你就这点水平吗
Is that the best you can do?
因为光这种不痛不痒的话
'Cause it's gonna take a little more than some
我一点没感觉
lame trash talk to get me out of my-
我靠 你搞毛啊
Gaah! What the hell was that?
我们的屁屁亲上了
Our butts pressed against each other.
没有亲上 只是隔空对望了一下
They didn't press. It was glancing.
别再说了
Stop talking about it!
得了 你又不是头一次来更衣室
Oh come on. All the time you've spent in a locker room,
肯定不是第一次"屁屁碰"了
this can't be your first moon landing.
-你还专门起了个名儿 -很平常啊
-You got a name for it? -It's very common.
你太不淡定了
You got off easy.
至少不是沐浴之后亲到的
At least it didn't happen after a shower.
-够了 -我们把那叫做"湿身吻"
-Enough. -We call that a splashdown.
够了 我去外面换 借过
That's it. I'm changing in the stall. Excuse me!
我看见那照片了 迪兰
I saw the picture, Dylan.
你手揽着她呢 表情还很猥亵
You had your arm around her with that humpy look you get.
滚 你平时才不是那表情 我们吹了
No, that's not always how you look. We're over!
我真的想和你谈谈 帕特森夫人
So, I'd really like to talk to you, Mrs. Patterson,
看看事情还有没有转机
see if we can't turn this thing around.
你有我电话吧
Uh, you've got my number.
谢谢
Thank you.
我说了我俩没戏了
I said we are over.
你可以骑车出去转转
Why don't you go out for a nice bike ride?
又是迪兰吧
Dylan again, huh?
有的男生就是笨得慌
Some guys just do not know how to play it.
-爸 你干啥呢 -噢 对了
-Dad, what are you doing? -Oh, right.
就是试试我的"滤汤器"[胡子]
Just, uh, test-driving my new soup strainer.
从万圣节杂物里翻出来的
I dug it out of the Halloween stuff
看看大家反应如何
to see what people think.
人们如果想做房地产咨询
Do people want their real estate advice...
是找"先锋派"还是"跟屁虫"呢
from someone who leads or from someone who follows?
我赌这胡子会再掀流行热潮
I'm betting these babies are coming back in a big way.
低买 高卖
Buy low, sell high.
大家肯定都会说 他可是"高"人[嗑药过量]
People are gonna see this and say, "That guy's high."
抱歉打扰了 先生
Sorry to bother you, sir.
我们在隔壁干活儿 弄破了主水管
We're doing work next door and nicked a main,
所以得把你家水停了
so we're gonna have to shut down your water.
好 没事
Oh. Okay. No problem.
应该不会太久 如果你要方便
It shouldn't be too long. If you happen to need it,
外边有个流动厕所
there's a porta-potty out front.
-谢了 那个 -什么
-Thanks. Hey. -Yeah.
胡子挺不错啊
Nice mustache.
嗯 你的也挺好 兄弟
Yeah, man. You too, brother.
你的也挺好 兄弟
"You too, brother."
海莉 她是长女 15岁了
Haley-She's the oldest. Fifteen.
然后是艾丽克斯 13岁
And then Alex is 13.
然后是我的小儿子 卢克 才11岁
And that's my baby, Luke. He's 11.
-不敢相信吧 -哇 他们真水灵
-Can you believe it? -Oh, my God, they're gorgeous.
-对啊 -和快乐男菲尔处得如何啊
-Yeah. -And things are still good with Phil the Thrill?
嗯 很棒 他好我也好
Yes. Things are great. Great with him.
我真为你开心 真的
I'm so happy for you. Really.
我真 我很开心你过得那么幸福
I'm so-I'm so happy that you're happy.
谢谢 你也是
Thank you. Well, and you too.
-你的人生真是 -别别 接着说你
-I mean, your life is -No, no, no-Let's talk about you.
-好吧 -因为你是...
-Okay. -Because, you know, you're
你选择了当妈 你成了一位母亲
You chose the mother. You're the mommy.
性感辣妈 妈妈 充满母爱
The yummy mommy, mama, person
你都快把我的戒指压进我的肉里去了
You're kinda squeezing the ring right into my finger.
是吗
Was I?
-有点 -不好意思啊
-A little. -I'm so sorry.
然后我突然意识到 她在嫉妒我
And just then, it hit me. She was jealous of me.
好吧 我们之间一直存在竞争
Yes, there'd always been a little bit of a competition between us.
此次可是重大比拼
This was more serious.
她觉得我的生活
She was looking at my life as something...
是她一直想要 却没得到的
that she'd always wanted, but never had.
谈谈你的职场生活啊
So how's life in the trenches?
23楼的那些混账老板
You still got the bastards on the 23rd floor...
让所有员工都生不如死
making life miserable for all the people actually doing the work.
-就是老样子呗 -有一点不同
-Same as ever, right? -One-one difference.
-什么 -我现在也是混账老板之一了
-Mm-hmm? -I'm one of them bastards now.
-等下 你混上23楼啦 -是24楼
-Wait. You're on the 23rd floor? -I'm on the 24th floor.
-哇 真牛啊 -也没啥啦
-Wow. That's insane. It's -It's no big deal.
如果你没离职 上去的也许会是你
I mean, if you hadn't left, it probably would have been you.
我就在路上开车啊
I was driving along this street.
那些车就像这样停在路边
The cars were parked just like this.
然后 嘭的一下 他就突然撞到我了
And boom, out of nowhere, he hits me.
-所以是他撞的你 -对
-Okay, so, he-he cut you off? -Yes.
-哦 -疯司机
-Right. -A crazy driver.
其实 我以前也像那样
You know, I used to be a little bit like that.
现在也许是因为莉莉吧 我也不知道
I don't know, maybe it's because of Lily,
我开车会更加小心 顾及他人
but I've definitely become more considerate.
我以前都不让别人"插"在我前面 现在会了
Like, I used to never let people in, and now I do.
我终于懂那个隐喻[插]的意思了 好吧
Just now getting that metaphor. Okay.
-你有何高见 -有目击证人吗
-So, what do you think? -Were there any witnesses?
没 只有曼尼 他当时在后座
No, just Manny. He was in the back seat.
-哦 -发生得太突然了 眨眼间啊
-Okay. -It all happened so fast--Just like they say.
好吧 行 接下来我们这样
Yeah. All right. Well, this is what we're gonna do.
我先拍几张照片
I'll take a few pictures,
然后坐下来起草一份声明
and then we'll sit down and write a statement.
真好 我去占个桌子
Perfect. I'll go and get us a table.
-行 -曼尼 你也来
-All right. -Manny, come.
-稍等 老妈 我鞋带散了 -好的
-Uh, just a minute, Mom. I need to tie my shoe. -Okay.
-米奇尔 -什么
-Mitchell. -Yeah?
别说话 听就好 责任在她
Don't talk. Listen. It was her fault.
-什么 我没听清 -别看着我
-I'm sorry. What? -Don't look at me.
别傻愣着 照相啊
Do something. Take pictures.
曼尼 你想要什么味道的蛋糕
Manny! What kind of cupcake do you want?
不用了 我不饿
Um, that's okay. I'm not hungry.
失误了 她现在肯定起疑心了
That was a mistake. Now she'II know something's up.
-你没事吧 -没事
-Are you okay? -I'm fine.
是她撞的那个司机 她驾驶技术超烂
She cut that guy off. She's a terrible driver.
-她是马路杀手 -慢点慢点
-She's a danger to us all. -Okay, wait. Now stop.
她不是说她的车是停着的 他撞了她吗
I thought she said he was parked and then he cut her off.
时速100英里 你看所有的车都是停着的
Everybody looks parked when you're going a hundred miles an hour.
曼尼 你之前为什么不说
Manny, why didn't you speak up?
她受不了别人批评她的驾驶技术
She can't take criticism about her driving.
有次一个老太太在十字路口冲她嚷嚷
Once an old lady yelled at her at a crosswalk.
她就一直鸣喇叭 最后喇叭都不响了
She honked so long, the horn ran out.
曼尼
Manny!
我已经透露得太多了
I've said too much already.
你听见了吗
Are you hearing this?
-我靠 -得分
- Aw, that's - Point.
妨碍[术语]
Hinder!
你走狗屎运
Lucky shot!
游戏结束 胜负分晓
That is game and, I believe, match.
好吧好吧 你赢了 但也难怪
Yeah, fine, you won. But, you know, what do you expect?
上半场的时候
For the first half of the game,
之前的更衣室事件 让我有些分心
I was distracted by what happened in the locker room.
你确定不是因为我打得很赞吗
And you're sure it's not because I'm a fabulous racquetball player?
你就一般水平 我心里一直纠结你碰了我
You're average. But I was a little thrown by you touching me.
很让人反感 但你肯定不觉得
Which is unnatural. Not to you, of course.
你肯定觉得很爽
No, to you it's like rocket fuel.
噢 是啊 基佬就"喜欢"到处
Oh, sure. When you're gay you just walk around
用屁股碰别人
giving butt bumps to everybody.
就像"击掌"一样 不过是"亲臀"罢了
It's like a high five. It's a low two.
跟你说 我要证明
You know what? I'm gonna prove
我输掉是因为分心了
that you won only because I was distracted.
我们现在再打一场
We're gonna have a rematch right here, right now.
-所以你想再和我"大干一场"吗 -对
-So you want to go up against me again? -Yes.
不 我靠
No! Damn it.
喂
Hello!
爸 你知道那车祸责任在歌洛莉亚吗
Hey, Dad. Uh, did you know that the accident was Gloria's fault?
嗯 我虽然当时不在场
Yes. I mean, I wasn't there,
但歌洛莉亚是个烂司机
but she's a horrible driver.
她要撞了10辆车 我也不吃惊
If she hit 10 cars, I wouldn't be surprised.
你既然知道是她的责任 为什么把我扯进来
If you knew it was her fault, why did you get me involved?
因为总得有人告诉她她错了
Because someone has to tell her she's in the wrong,
你说总比我说好
and better you than me.
真好啊 我还天真地以为
That's great. Here I am thinking
我爸开始尊重我律师的职业了
that my dad actually respects me as a lawyer,
但你只是把我往火坑里推
and really you're just throwing me to the wolves.
-不能两种心思都有吗 -好吧
-Can't it be both? -Okay.
老爸 你就一点没觉得悲哀
Dad, it doesn't bother you in the least...
你的同性恋儿子是唯一
that your gay son is the only one
敢直面你老婆的人
tough enough to stand up to your wife?
加油搞定吧伙计 回见
Go get 'em, Rocky. See you later.
你老爸和我在更衣室"屁屁碰"了
Your father and I had a moon landing in the locker room.
你有病啊
What's the matter with you?
你呢 有没有在处对象啊
What about you? Do you ever get serious with anyone?
没有 目前没有
Sure. Oh, no. Not yet.
宝贝 你会有的
Oh, honey, you will.
不 我不希望有 现在很好玩
Oh, no, I hope not. It's-It's fun.
不好意思 我在等电话
I'm sorry. I'm just-I'm waiting for some news.
-什么电话 -我去应聘了一个法国的工作
-What news? -I'm-I'm up for the Paris job.
国际分公司的头头吗
The-The head of the international division?
那 那也太牛了
That's-That's-That's crazy.
嗯 没啦 我应该聘不上的 聘上当然好
Yeah, no. I mean, I'll never get it, but it'd be great...
因为我情夫之一在巴黎呢
'cause one of my lovers lives in Paris.
哇 我都不知道那句话中哪个词更震撼
Wow. I-I don't know what jumps out of that sentence more-
又是"情夫"又是"之一"的
you know, "Lovers" Or "One of."
我单身嘛 就是要这样啊
Well, I'm single. I mean, it's kinda what you do.
-嗯哼 -有个在巴黎
-Uh-huh. -I have one in Paris.
巴黎 纽约 迈阿密各有一个
Um, I have Paris, New York, Miami.
其实还有一个
I have a fourth one.
-我都忘了我的情夫了 真要命 -嗯
-I'm forgetting one lover. I'm forgetting one lover. -Mmm.
昨晚我把冰箱下面的散热器打扫了下
Last night I vacuumed the radiator thingy under the fridge.
太沾灰了
You know, it collects the dust.
平时就该清理的 我也忘了
Cause you should, and I don't. So-
等下 为我祈祷吧
Oh, hey, hold on. Cross your fingers.
说实话
I'm not gonna lie.
一想到瓦莱丽会得到
The thought of Valerie getting the one job
那份大家都想要的工作
in the whole company that everyone coveted
我心里可不怎么"情"愿
well, I wasn't a "Lover" Of that.
嗯 嗯 谢谢
Okay. Okay, thank you.
如何
Well?
他们还没定呢
Oh, they haven't made a decision.
他们说回头再告诉我
They're-they're gonna tell me later on.
-他们不是这么说的吧 -是啦
- That's not what they said, is it? - Uh, yeah, it is.
拜托 瓦莱丽 我不是外人
Oh, Valerie, come on. It's me.
朋友就该相互支持
What are friends for,
再坏的事情都可以跟我说
if not to be there for you when you get bad news?
-我聘上了 -天呐 啊
-I got it. -Oh, my God. Aaah!
-我是欧洲的头儿啦 -酒店头儿啦
- I'm the head of Europe. - Well, you know, for the hotel-
-不是整个欧洲 -差不多啦 差不多
- Not the continent. - Kind of though. Kind of.
你一开始为什么不告诉我呢
Why didn't you tell me when you first heard?
噢 因为 那个
Oh, 'cause, you know
然后我才恍然大悟
And that's when it really hit me.
瓦莱丽才不嫉妒我 她可怜我
Valerie wasn't jealous of me. She pitied me.
我当时有点想把她带回家
And part of me wanted to take her back to the house...
让她看看我有而她没有的东西
and show her everything she was missing...
她真悲哀 没有孩子 没有老公
in her sad, childless, husbandless life.
但我知道"高风亮节"四个字儿咋写
But there's a little thing called "Taking the high road."
等下你到我家喝杯茶呗
Why don't you come by and meet everybody?
好啊 那挺好的
Oh, sure. That'd be great.
是啊 艾丽克斯就是个小天才啊
Yeah, I mean, Alex is just a genius,
海莉真是女大十八变
and Haley is turning into this beautiful young woman,
-她让我懂得了做母亲... -旧金山
-and it makes me realize that motherhood is -San Francisco.
-最重要的是 -我第四个情人 在旧金山
- The most important - That was my fourth lover. San Francisco.
-想不起来我今晚肯定睡不着 -嗯
- It would have kept me up all night. - Yeah.
老爸 快看
Dad, look.
等会儿 小家伙 我去上趟厕所
Just a sec, buddy. I'm on my way out to the bathroom.
你看 昨晚奥布里一家开了个巨型派对
Check it out. The Aubreys had this huge party last night,
瓶子都归我们了
and we got all these bottles to recycle.
-恭喜 -野格酒是什么
-Great. -What's Jegermeister?
那个...在童话故事里
Well, you know how in a fairy tale...
都会有种让公主睡着的药
there's always a potion that makes the princess fall asleep,
然后男生们就去亲她
and then the guys start kissing her?
野格酒也差不多 不同的是你醒来不是在城堡
Well, this is like that, except you don't wake up in a castle,
而是在兄弟会的房子 然后从此臭名远扬
you wake up in a frat house with a bad reputation.
海莉
Haley!
-卢克 都洒出来了啦 -擦
- Luke, you're spilling it! - Aw, crud.
天
God
耗子 好恶心
Gross! A rat!
酷
Cool.
等着 来了来了
Hang on. I'm coming.
你拿了我的一样东西
I believe you have something that belongs to me.
我的心
My heart.
我在网上说了让你滚远点
I thought I I.M.'ed you to stay away.
嗷 海莉
Ow! Haley.
喂 迪兰 迪迪仔
Hello? Dylan? D-Money?
嘿 老兄 老兄
Hey, buddy! Hey, buddy!
嗨 左邻右舍们
Hello, friendly neighbors!
求帮忙啊
Little help?
可是我爱你
But I love you.
你之前怎么没想到你爱我啊
Well, you should have thought about that...
你竟然带莎伦·妮可利那个小婊子
before you took that skank Sharon Nicolini
去看安妮·海瑟薇的电影
to an Anne Hathaway movie.
我没带她去 只是碰巧遇到
I didn't take her. She was just there.
你就一个人去看安妮·海瑟薇的电影吗
So you were just there by yourself at an Anne Hathaway movie?
别忽悠我了
I don't think so!
是啊 我很喜欢她的电影
Yeah. Yeah. I like her movies.
她是个出色的女人 求求你 别闹了吧
She's every woman. Come on. Let's not fight.
坐下来 像两个不成熟的成年人那样谈谈吧
Let's just discuss this like two un-immature adults.
你好 帕特森太太
Hello? Mrs. Patterson.
嗨 我正等你电话呢
Hi. I've been waiting for your call.
嗯 我们可不可以再仔细谈一谈
Yeah. Uh, is there any chance that maybe we could talk a little bit-
没没没 挺好的 真挺好的
No, no, no, no. Now's perfect. That's fine.
不好意思 我这边吵 等我把办公室门关上
I'm sorry. I couldn't hear you. Let me just close my office door.
好了 能听清了
There we go. Much, much better.
我们再来回顾一下车祸的情形吧
Okay. Maybe, uh, we should go over the accident one more time.
一丝不"狗"地分析 你真是个好律师啊
Put the dogs on a row. You're such a good lawyer.
我就是想确保
Uh, I just wanna make sure
一定要搞清楚真实的情况
we're 100% clear on exactly what happened.
已经很清楚了啊 我跟你说了啊
Oh, we're clear. I told you.
怎么 你不信我吗
What? You don't believe me?
没 没 我只是
No, no. I just-
你知道 有时候会漏掉一些细节嘛
You know, sometimes you can forget tiny details.
比如 有没有可能 是你开太快了
Like, is it possible, maybe, uh, you were driving too fast?
-谁说我开太快了 -对 谁说的
-Who said I was driving fast? -Yeah, who?
我看着街上
I just-I'm looking at the street,
就想 如果你开得很快的话
and I'm thinking if you were driving a little fast,
你就有可能
it's possible that maybe you
-没看见那车 -你也跟他们一样
- didn't see the car - You're like everyone else, huh?
一切都是我们拉丁人的错
You blame the Latino driver.
在我们老家 总是把错都推给拉丁司机
Where I come from, they always blame the Latino driver.
你们老家不是所有司机都是拉丁司机吗
Where you come from, isn't everybody a Latino driver?
-曼尼 你跟他说 -没法说啊 我吃蛋糕呢
- Manny, tell him. - I can't 'cause I have a cupcake in my mouth.
得了吧 别拿蛋糕当挡箭牌
Oh, come on. Don't blame your cupcake.
怎么 你也觉得是我的错吗
What? You think I'm guilty too?
-没啦 -得
- No. - Fine.
我不要你做我的律师了
I don't need you as a lawyer anymore.
你俩不是觉得我是个烂司机吗
And if you two think I'm such a bad driver,
你们走回家好了
you're safer walking home.
拜拜
Chao.
-就这儿了 -真好
- Here it is. - It's really cute.
嗯 我们都很以此为豪呢
Yeah. We're pretty proud of it.
你的烂CD 拿着
Here's your stupid CDs...
你的烂衣服 还有狗屎诗
and your clothes and your poems!
-你敢扔试试 -我就敢了
- Don't you do it! - Oh, I'm doing it.
海莉 停手 你在干啥呢
Haley, stop it. What are you doing?
折磨我的心
Tearing out my heart.
那你去让莎伦·妮可利给你个吻痕啊
Oh, why don't you go get a hickey from Sharon Nicolini?
那是我吉他带子勒的 海莉
It's from my guitar strap, Haley.
-噢 谢谢你提醒我扔吉他 -那是我女儿海莉
-Oh, thanks for reminding me. -That's my daughter Haley
然后她男朋友 迪兰
And her boyfriend, Dylan, um
粉刷的颜色真漂亮
This is a nice color.
恩 是这样的 我家平时不这样
Yeah. Um, listen. This is not normal,
没这么 靠 是酒的气味吗
with all that, nor-nor is that liquor smell.
菲尔 宝贝 天 卢克 这是咋了
Phil, honey? Oh, my God. Luke, what is that?
野格酒 老爸说它可以让女生更容易亲
Jegermeister. Dad says it makes girls easier to kiss.
-那地毯是怎么回事 -出了点小意外
- What happened to the rug? - I had an accident.
好吧 艾丽克斯 你又在干嘛
Okay. Alex, what are you doing?
我在追杀一只耗子
I'm trying to kill a rat.
好吧
Okay
莎伦在帮我给你挑生日礼物
Sharon was helping me buy you a birthday present.
你不明白吗 我爱的是你的屁股蛋蛋
Don't you get it? I love your ass.
那个...我 我快迟了 得走了
I-You know, I-I-I'm late and I should go.
-我知道 我知道 -嗯
-I know. I know. -Yeah.
今天的确是有点乱糟糟的
And it seems like things have gotten a little wonky around here.
不知道菲尔上哪儿了 他肯定...
I don't know where Phil is. He's definitely-
老天啊 艾丽克斯
Oh, my God. Alex
你爸呢
Where's your father?
他去外面上厕所了
He went outside to go to the bathroom.
平时真不这样的 靠 刺瞎我的眼
It's... not usually like this. Oh, gross.
-我们结婚吧 -好
- Let's just get married. - Okay.
你不会后悔的 帕特森太太
You will not regret this decision, Mrs. Patterson.
跟你说
And I'll tell you what.
我请你到我家来庆祝下
We're gonna have you over to our little house to celebrate.
-好吗 嗯 拜拜 -有空再来啊
- Okay? Okay, bye-bye. - You should come back again-
-有空就来 -克莱尔 克莱尔
- sometime, when you get a break - Claire! Claire!
菲尔 你 你干啥呢
Phil, what are you-what are you doing?
忙着谈业务呢
Just concluding a little business.
顺便补一句 很顺利噢
Very successfully, I might add.
-宝贝 -嘿
- Honey - Hey!
-你好 -你不是瓦莱丽嘛
- Hi. - Is that Valerie?
-嗯 -哇
- Yeah. - Wow!
-你真漂亮 -谢谢
- You look fantastic. - Thank you.
来来来 过来
Come here. Get over here.
好吧
Okay.
-我们多久没见了 -很久了
- How long has it been? - A long time.
噢 老天啊
Oh, my goodness.
-我没办法触到你 -是有点难
- Oh, I can't touch you. Okay. - A little bit difficult.
隔车相望
Gulf divides us, eh?
-见到你真好 -可不是嘛
- So nice to see you. - It's great to see you though
-嗯 -好吧
- Okay. - All right.
-走了啊 -有空来坐坐
- Okay, then. - Thanks for coming by.
-谢谢招待 -拜拜
- It's such a pleasure. - Bye-bye.
-有空常来啊 -你家真漂亮
- Thanks for stopping by. - You have a beautiful family.
-她真漂亮 是吧 -你脸上是什么玩意儿
- She looks great, doesn't she? - What is on your face?
一次 哪怕一次
One time! Once!
我带个客人回家
One time I bring somebody home...
想刺激一下别人 结果呢
who I want to impress, and what do I find?
一个全身酒味的
A bunch of booze-drenched hill people...
穿着内裤到处走 一个追耗子的
just sitting around in their underwear and-and chasing rats...
还有一个在楼梯口就搞起来的
and fornicating in the stairwell.
-我能插句话吗 -不准插 超级玛丽
- Can I say something? - No. No, you can't, Mario.
你什么都不用说了 谢谢
There is nothing left to say but thank you.
谢谢你们
Thank you all.
早说了你打不过我
I told you I'd win.
现在没话可说了吧 神球手
Not talking so much now, are you, hotshot?
希望你洗澡洗个爽
Hope you enjoy that nice, hot shower,
但15比7的耻辱你是洗不掉的
but it's not gonna wash away the shame of that 15-7 beatdown.
你真该看看你当时的表情
You should have seen the look on your face...
球和墙亲密接触那瞬间
when that drop shot just kissed the wall.
好吧 湿身吻
Ah. Okay, splashdown.
又弄到我了 是吧
Got me again. Yep.
让我这传统直男情何以堪
Make the uptight straight guy all embarrassed.
但是 我还就真无所谓了
Except for one thing -doesn't even bother me anymore.
我可以一直这样碰 来 再碰一个
I could do this all day. Here, another one for you.
再多来几次啊
Maybe a couple of 'em.
杰 我发现后面有个桑拿哟
Jay, I just noticed a sauna back here.
-我们要冲进去吗 -像赶着投胎那样冲进去
-How big of a hurry are we in? -Biggest hurry of your life.
借过 借过
'Scuse me. 'Scuse me.
如果注定了要被困住[进退两难]
Well, if you're going to be stranded,
不如就被困在蛋糕店吧
might as well be in a place full of cupcakes.
我看你吃得差不多了
I don't think you need any more.
啊 真是不好意思
Ay. I'm sorry, guys.
的确 我喜欢为自己抗辩
It's true. I am a defensive driver.
-你是说你喜欢抗辩... -我知道自己什么样
-You mean you're defensive about -I know what I am.
我们走吧
Let's go.
只是我不喜欢大家凭空就
It's just that I don't like when people just assume
说我是个烂司机
that I'm a bad driver.
也许我是要 负那么一点点责任
Maybe it was just, like, a little bit my fault.
你能承认 挺好的
Well, I'm glad you can admit that, Gloria.
但我还是想让你当我的律师 米奇
But I'm still gonna need you as my lawyer, Mitch.
-为什么 -因为眼前的惨剧
-Why? -Because this one
完全不关我的事 我保证
It was not my fault, I promise you.
原来那巨响是这个啊
That's what that sound was.
都是这蛋糕招牌的错
It was the big cupcake.
简直难以置信 老妈疯了
That was unreal. Mom was crazy.
我好怕怕
I'm scared.
听着 我了解你妈这个人 她没事的
Look. I know your mom pretty well. She's fine.
我猜她现在在努力控制情绪呢
I'd be willing to bet she's just composing herself,
在公园里静静散步呢
taking a nice, long, peaceful walk in the park.
好极了
Perfect.
那会儿我只想回家
At that moment all I wanted was to be with my family.
但回去肯定要想办法道歉
But of course, that meant finding a way to apologize...
我说话太重 伤了他们
to the people that I had belittled and rejected.
你乱说啥呢 那歌多好听啊
Okay, you are so crazy. That song totally rules.
-老爸 你才乱说呢 -明明很有道理
-Daddy, you're crazy. -Crazy right.
-嘿 宝贝 -嗨
-Hey, honey. -Hi.
嘿 老妈 来坐啊
Hey, Mom. Come on. Sit down.
真的 老爸 烂透了
No, seriously, Dad. It's lame.
真的 卢克 不烂
Seriously, Luke. It's not.
你脸上有芥末还是什么的
You got some mustard or something on your face.
关于音乐我还是懂点的
I think I know a little bit about music.
读大学时我还当过DJ呢
I was a DJ in college.
拥有一档在黄金时间播放的节目
I had my own show in the coveted time slot.
-《与邓菲一起等待黎明》 -真的假的
-Daybreak with Dunphy. -Are you kidding me?
骗你干啥 我播瑞克·艾斯里的歌哦
No, I'm not kidding you. And I played Rick Astley.
-老爸 你囧死我了 -绝不放弃 卢克 跟着唱啊
-Dad, that's embarrassing. -Never gonna give, Sing it, Luke.
他们原本大可以记恨我的
They could have been petty.
他们大可以为难我 但他们没有
They really could have made me pay, but they didn't.
爱死他们了
Never loved 'em more.
为毛瓦莱丽就看不到他们的这一面呢
Why the hell couldn't Valerie have seen them like that?
嘿 迪兰
Hey, Dylan.
你好 邓菲先生
Hey, Mr. Dunphy.
你干啥呢
What's happening?
海莉又跟我闹了
Well, Haley and I got into another fight.
《情到深处》的场景呀[说点什么吧]
Oh. Say Anything.
早上好?
Um, good morning?
-不 情到深处[随便说点什么] -报纸
-No. Say Anything. -Newspaper.
不 迪兰 《情到深处》 经典电影
No, Dylan. Say Anything. Clutch movie.
经典电影
Clutch movie.
她应该要过几个小时才醒
She probably won't be up for a couple hours still.
没事 手机没多重
It's okay. It's not that heavy.